Finding Aid for Lorenzo Davis papers, 1822-1899
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lorenzo Davis papers 1822-1899
Davis, Lorenzo, 1812-
0.6 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
851220 Aa 2
Washtenaw County, Michigan minister, local historian and public official; correspondence, sermons, and collected papers relating to the history of Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County, Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was transferred from the Graduate Library of the University of Michigan (donor no. 1278 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Lorenzo Davis was born in Covington, N.Y., April 29, 1812, the son of Jonathan E. and Hannah (Curtis) Davis, natives of Massachusetts. His father was a farmer, teacher and itinerant Methodist Episcopal minister. In 1828, Lorenzo moved to Ypsilanti only to return to New York in 1829, then back again to Michigan in 1831. In 1834 Davis obtained a license to preach, and was received into the Ohio conference, which then included the Michigan Territory. He was pastor in various Michigan communities before finally settling in Ann Arbor in 1845 where he both preached and clerked in a drug store. In his life, Davis had many activities and interests: as a publisher, farmer, as register of deeds for two years, as town clerk and superintendent of the poor, as active member of the Washtenaw County Pioneer Society, and member and secretary of the Agricultural Society of Washtenaw County.
Except for a scattering of correspondence and sermon notes, the bulk of the Davis collection relates to the Washtenaw County Pioneer Society and to the history of Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County. Included is correspondence of Ezra and William S. Maynard, biographies of early pioneers, papers relating to the development of the temperance movement in Washtenaw County, the history of Northfield, Sylvan, and Ypsilanti Townships, Michigan; papers, 1881, concerning the First Congregational Church of Salem Township, Michigan; and papers, 1866, concerning the Ann Arbor Sunday School Convention.
Subjects:
Congregational Churches--Michigan--Salem.; Farmers--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Frontier and pioneer life--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Northfield (Mich.: Township); Salem (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township); Sylvan (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township); Temperance--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Washtenaw County (Mich.); Washtenaw County (Mich.). Board of the Superintendents of the Poor.; Washtenaw County Historical Society.; Ypsilanti (Mich.: Township)
Contributors:
Maynard, William Sumner, 1802-1866.; Maynard, Ezra.
Genre Terms:
Sermons.
- Personal and collected material
  - Correspondence, 1822-1899 (Box 1)
    (include correspondence with William S. Maynard)
  - Newspaper clippings concerning the meetings of Washtenaw County Pioneer Society, 1870s (Box 1)
  - Recollections by Davis of the early ministers of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - History of Ann Arbor by Lorrin Mills read to the Washtenaw County Pioneer Society, 1877 (Box 1)
  - History of Ann Arbor by Thomas Holmes; and other historical and biographical notes (Box 1)
  - Papers relating to the history of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the board of the superintendents of the poor of Washtenaw County, 1833 (Box 1)
  - History of the temperance movement in Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - Minutes of the Washtenaw County Pioneer Society, 1878-1879 (Box 1)
  - Receipts of Eagle Fire Company, No. 1, 1864 (Box 1)
  - Paper concerning the First Congregational Church of Salem Township, Washtenaw County, 1881 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the Ann Arbor Sunday School Convention, 1866 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the history of Ypsilanti, Sylvan, and Northfield townships (Box 1)
  - Map of the Navarre farm on the Raisin River, 1838 (Box 1)
  - Records of the bounty paid on the scalps of woodchucks, 1885-1886 (Box 1)
  - Sermons: Lorenzo Davis, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Biographies of early residents of Washtenaw County (Box 1)
  - List of Washtenaw County residents willing to serve in home guard, 1861 (Box 1)
  - Personal notebook (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Road assessments, 1881-1885, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - School censuses and reports, 1881-1886 (Box 2)